## Andre Kuhlenschmidt

Contact Information Luddy Hall E-mail: akuhlens@iu.edu Indiana University Phone: (812) 325-7906 700 N. Woodlawn Ave. Github: github.com/akuhlens Bloomington, IN 47408 WWW: akuhlens.github.io

Research Interests I am interested in designing and building compilers, runtime systems, and type systems that make it easier to produce quality software. My most recent work focuses on the implementation of type systems that provide the benefits from both static and dynamic typing (i.e. gradual typing) while minimizing overhead.

**EDUCATION** 

Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana USA

Ph.D. Candidate, Computer Science, May 2020

Advisor: Jeremy Siek

M.S., Computer Science, May 2016 May 2010

B.S., Business, Major: Entrepreneurship,

EXPERIENCE

Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana USA

Graduate Research Assistant

January 2014 - Present

- Evaluate implementation techniques for sound gradually typed programming languages.
- Develop an ahead of time compiler Grift.
- Measure performance improvements in compiler via benchmark experiments.
- Design semantics that facilitate safety and efficiency.

Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana USA

Assistant Instructor

January 2016 - May 2018 August 2012 - May 2014

- Planned and constructed course materials and software for courses in programming language semantics and implementation, operating systems, and embedded systems.
- Instructed labs sessions of 5-30 students.
- Recognized as Assistant Instructor of the Year in 2018.

SKILLS

Languages: Racket, C, Haskell, Java, Python, Coq, C++

Tools and Platforms: Bash, Git, Make, Linux, Mac OS, Chibi OS, ARM

Workshop Papers

An Efficient Compiler for the Gradually Typed Lambda Calculus Andre Kuhlenschmidt, Deyaaeldeen Almahallawi, Jeremy G. Siek. In Scheme and Functional Programming Workshop, 2018.

A Systematic Performance Evaluation of Gradually Typed Functions and References. Andre Kuhlenschmidt, Deyaaeldeen Almahallawi, Jeremy G. Siek. In Scripts to Programs Workshop, STOP, 2016.

Towards Absolutely Efficient Gradual Typing Andre Kuhlenschmidt, Deyaaeldeen Almahallawi, and Jeremy G. Siek. In Scripts to Programs Workshop, STOP, 2015.

OPEN SOURCE Projects

Grift

May 2014 - Present

- Lead developer of an optimizing compiler for a gradually typed Lisp to native code.
- Utilizes space-efficient coercions to enforce soundness of the static type system.

Professional ACTIVITIES

IU SICE Graduate Education Committee, Student Representative OOPSLA Artifact Evaluation Committee SPLASH Student Research Competition Program Committee

Spring – Fall 2018 August 2018 August 2018